现在我们了解了
Now we get to some knowledge and
我们将会有不同的知识部分
we're gonna have different
knowledge portions of this course.
我想从 Big-O 开始，因为它有点被误解了。
I want to start with Big-O because it's
something that is a little misunderstood.
我不知道是否应该有连字符。
I don't know if it should be hyphenated or
not.
我相信它看起来更酷了
I believe it hyphenated
cuz it looks cooler.
Big-O我是说什么是 Big-O
Big-O, I mean, what is Big-O?
有人告诉我这会有很多的
Someone tell me, and
this will come up a lot.
我要问你一些问题
Some of the questions I'm gonna ask you,
我要说，你刚才写的这个功能的 Big-O 是什么呢 ?
I'm going to say, what's the Big-O
of this function you just wrote?
嗯。
Yeah.
> > 我可以尝试。
&gt;&gt; I can try.
Big-O 表示法的类型类似于您用于确定时间长度的公式
Big-O notation is kinda of like the
formula that you use to determine how long
就像个问题一样
something's gonna take, like a problem.
或者其实我只是把它当作一个问题
Or actually I've only
used it as a problem,
我从没用过这种东西我不知道你能不能
I've never used it for anything else,
I don't know if you can.
所以， > 嗯，不过是最长的
So,
&gt;&gt; Yeah, well but it's the longest
鉴于输入的情况最差情况，任何函数都将被执行。
amount any function is going to take,
given the worst case scenario of input.
作为工程师，作为计算机科学家，我们应该知道 Big-O是重要的。
It's important to know as engineers, as
computer scientists, we should know Big-O.
因为你在想我的功能
Because you're thinking, my function that,
我不知道，我写的我的功能，它在它里是有循环的。
I don't know, my function that I wrote,
that it has for-loops in it.
我只需要 100 个元素就可以了
I only have 100 elements to iterate over,
fine.
但如果你写了几十亿元素的东西
But if you write things that
take billions of elements,
然后你就知道时间是在爬爬爬来的
then you see that time creep up,
and creep up, and creep up.
知道 Big-O 是很重要的
Knowing Big-O is really important.
但因为它正试图主宰一切，我要你主宰所有的大人们。
But because it's trying to masters,
I want you to master all the Bigs.
大欧米茄大公司大公司
Big Omega, Big Theta, Big O.
你不需要知道大 Q 和大西塔
You don't have to know Big Omega and
Big Theta.
我觉得这才叫知识，因为大多数人说大澳，
I think it's just called knowledge to
have because most people say Big O,
我们知道这是件好事
we know it's a thing.
但是有个大 Q
But there's Big Omega.
大 Q 描述了最好的情况
Big Omega describes
the best case scenario,
输入的理想情况的操作复杂性。
the operational complexity of
the ideal case of your input.
如果一切顺利的话它会很快地运行
If all things go well,
it's gonna run really, really quickly, and
那是最好的情况
that's the best case.
" 大数 " 是平均个案。
Big theta is the average case.
那么平均而言
Well, on average, or
确切的情况，它会在这个复杂程度上运行，这次。
the precise case, it's gonna run
at this complexity, this time.
大 O 是最坏的情况
And big O is the worst case.
你在想为什么计算机科学家如此悲观
And you're thinking, why are computer
scientists so pessimistic,
他们只关心大澳吗
they only care about Big O?
是啊在大欧米茄上运行是很棒的
Yes, it's awesome when
things run on Big omega.
但一般来说我们在乎大澳大的时间
But generally,
we care about the Big O time,
因为我们想知道最坏的情况
because we wanna know about
the worst-case scenario.
在此功能中可能发生的最慢的可能是什么 ?
What is the slowest possible thing
that can happen in this function?
所以在这种情况下，这个搜索函数只对一个数组进行迭代
So in this case, this search function
which just iterates over an array, and
如果它找到了它想要的号码
if it finds whatever
number it's looking for,
如果找不到它就会回到真实的状态
it's gonna return true, if it doesn't
find it's gonna return false.
所以这个搜索功能最好的原因是我有一个
So the best case with this search
function because I have one for
循环，这意味着我要对元素进行迭代一次，但我提前返回。
loop, which means I'm iterating over
the elements one time, but I return early.
因此，最好的情况是元素零。
So the best case is element zero.
指数零点的元素是我要找的东西，我们会变成真实的。
Element at index zero is the thing I'm
looking for, we're going to turn true.
所以，我们要说的是 " 大 O " 或 " 大 Q " ，它是恒定的时间。
So, we're gonna say that's Big O one or
Big omega one, which is constant time.
它马上就要回来了
It's gonna return instantly.
不管我们的数据里有多少元素
And it doesn't matter how many
elements are in our data set,
不管它是十亿还是一万亿还是一万亿
it doesn't matter if it's a billion or
a trillion or a gazillion.
我不确定刊宪是数字，但第一个元素不重要
I'm not sure if gazillion is a number, but
it doesn't matter if the first element is
我们要找的东西马上就会回来了
the thing we're looking for, it's going to
return immediately so it's constant time.
大 Q
Big omega.
大 θ 是平均时间。
Big theta is the average time.
平均而言，我们可能要迭代整个数组或
On average, we'll probably have to
iterate through the entire array or
我们平均得用一半的时间来迭代
we'll say on average we're gonna have
to iterate through half the array.
你跟踪吗
You follow?
比如如果我们有一个巨大的数据，我们就得过去
Like if we had a giant data set on
average, we're gonna have to go through
它的一半是为了找到我们在一个均匀分布的数据集合中寻找的东西
half of it to find the thing we're looking
for in an evenly distributed data set.
这实际上是大数据在 2 个以上的数据中，我们将要处理的元素的一半
So that's actually Big data n over 2 cuz
that's half of the elements we're going
来迭代，但我们总是舍弃这些额外的数字，所以它只是大数据 n。
to iterate over, but we always drop those
extra numbers so it's just big data n.
而 n 当然是你穿越的元素的数量
And n is of course the number of
elements you're traversing, or
数据集的大小。
the size of data set.
它可能意味着很多事情，但通常是时间或元素的数量。
It can mean a lot of things, but
it's generally time or number of elements.
所以，平均有 n 个以上的数据，我们可以称之为 n。
So big data on average n over
2 which we just could call n.
大 O 的情况也是 n。
The Big O case is also n.
所以说那是个回返案
So let's say that's the return false case.
你没找到所有你要找的要素最坏的情况
You didn't find the element all of you
are looking for, at the worst case,
我们要对整个数据集进行迭代
we're gonna have to iterate through
the entire data set, the entire array.
就像我们找不到的东西一样酷
And it's like the thing we're looking for
isn't there, cool.
所以在这个功能最糟糕的情况下
So in the very worst
case of this function,
我们会说它是 Big-O n ，希望能和 Big-O 有一点帮助。
we're going to say it's Big-O n, hopefully
that helps with Big-O a little bit.
我知道这威胁着人们的身份一棵树来登录它的登录
I know it's intimidating cuz people be
like, a tree to access its login or
他们会把你想记住的数字扔出去
they'll just throw out numbers
that you expect to memorize.
但不要把它保存得更能真正地接受这些
But instead of memorizing it's better
to really take these to heart.
我给你看下戏法，我给你看看 Jem 的戏法
I'll show you the trick,
I'll show you the Jem trick at the end for
和你说你是很有道理的人
figuring out big-O and when you
say you're like, that makes sense.
希望我能做得好
Hopefully if I'm doing things right.
我们在乎大 O 因为我可以说它是大澳 2n
And we care about big O because I can say,
it's big-O 2n or
大 O n 的平方不一定意味着什么
big O n squared,
that doesn't necessarily mean anything,
当你看一张图要跑多久，就不要想 10 或
when you look at a graph of how long
things take to run, so don't think 10 or
100，思考十亿个元素，时间复杂度会增加。
100, think a billion elements,
that timing complexity adds up.
因此，大 -O n factorial 是最糟糕的时间。
So big -O n factorial is
the worst possible time.
" 组织 " 说这就是 " 砰 " 的标志
Factorial is say, so that's the bang sign,
或者惊叹号不管你想说什么
or exclamation point,
whatever you wanna call it.
因此，阶乘 4 是 2 乘以 1的 4 倍，这是事实。
So factorial 4 would be 4 times 3
times 2 times 1, that's factorial.
那是最糟糕的时候了
That's the worst possible time.
非常不寻常，如果你写点东西，就能得到大 O 的阶乘时间。
It's very unusual, if you write something,
to get big O factorial time.
但是别这样你的功能就永远不会结束了
But just don't, your function
will pretty much never finish,
情况会越来越糟
it'll just get worse and worse.
2n 的平方
2n, n squared,
这些都是你想要逃避的可怕的时刻
those are all terrible running times
you want to avoid things like that.
我们进入了一段合理的时间，我们进入了 n 个日志。
We get to a little bit reasonable times,
we get to n log n.
所以我和我不去做什么对数函数
So the trick and I won't go into
what logarithmic means, but
如果你对数据集进行迭代
the trick is think if you're
iterating over a data set, and
每次迭代时都要减少元素数量
every time you iterate,
you're reducing the number of elements
就像在过滤需要迭代的元素数一样。
as in you're filtering the number of
elements you need to iterate over.
这将会是每次都要记录的时间。
That's going to be log time every time.
因此，提供了一个良好的日志时间示例。
So giving a good example of log time.
我们会得到一些日志时间树
We'll get some examples that are log time,
trees,
tree 元素作为树是日志时间，因为树是有序的。
funny element as a tree is log
time because trees are ordered.
所以我看着这里，我说，让我们说一个二进制搜索树。
So I look here and I say,
on let's say a binary search tree.
这个元素是大还是小我要走了
Is this element bigger or
smaller, I'm gonna go left.
越大或越小，向右，向左或向右。
Bigger or smaller,
go right, go left or right.
所以没有时间对整个树进行迭代来找到我要找的东西
So, and no time iterating over the entire
tree to find the thing I'm looking for,
这就是为什么它的记录时间
that's why it's log time,
因为每次我都在减少可能的比赛次数
because every time I'm reducing
the number of possible matches.
大澳，就是基地的情况，就是说我们
Big O n, that is kind of the base case,
that means we
迭代整个数据集以执行我们正在尝试的任何操作。
iterated through the entire data set
to do whatever we're trying to do.
会有很多事情发生的
That's gonna happen a lot.
通常，您将其视为整个数据集的循环重复。
Generally, you see it as a for
loop reiterating over the entire dataset.
最坏的情况可能是最常见的情况
Worst case scenario,
that's probably the most common case.
日志 n 是，就像我之前说过的，
Log n is, like I said before you're
reducing the number of elements that
在日志 n 和 n 之间，我要对整个数据集进行迭代。
are between log n and n is, I'm going to
have to iterate over the entire data set.
但当我做每一次的迭代时，我将缩小我所寻找的东西。
But as I do every single iteration, I'm
going to narrow down what I'm looking for.
而且 log n，这不太棒。
And log n, it's not great.
这不是可怕的足球
It's not terrible soccer.
就在中间的某个地方
It's somewhere in the middle there.
每当你写任何算法时你总是在努力
What you're always striving whenever
you're writing any sort of algorithm
你想用快速的时间来记录
you want log n time cuz that's fast,
它的时间不超过 1，这意味着它没有
that's short of constant time which is
bigger than 1, which means it doesn't
我们所做的事情总是会回到同一时间
matter what we're doing it's always
gonna return to the same time.
不管它们是十亿还是万亿
It doesn't matter if they're billion or
trillion,
它会同时返回的四倍
quadrillion it's always
gonna return the same time.
但在不断的时间里写东西很困难，所以 log n。
But it's pretty hard to write
things in constant time, so log n.
我知道我说的很像计算机科学术语
I know I'm saying a lot of like
computer sciency terms, but
有很多公司会问你，大澳大的时间是多少 ?
a lot of companies will ask you,
what's the big O time?
便宜的是这个和理解之类的，好的，
The cheap is looking at something
like this and understanding, okay,
忘了大 Q大数据他们很想知道
forget big omega, big data,
they're fun to know.
如果你把它扔出去，我就会说，哇，这个人挺聪明的。
And if you throw that out, I'll be like,
woah, this person is pretty smart.
他们比我聪明
They're smarter than me.
我想听听他们要说什么
I wanna hear what they have to say.
但我所使用的方法是用数字四环来观察循环数
But the trick I use is looking at number
four loops looking at number of loops, and
就像作弊一样
that's like the cheating way.
那么，如果一个循环是 big-O n，
So, if one for loop is big-O n,
这到底是什么东西
what's the big-O of this?
>> n 到第三个。
&gt;&gt; n to the third.
> > 对， n 个 cubed， n 到第三个。
&gt;&gt; Yes, n cubed, n to the third.
因为我们反复迭代然后每次迭代都要迭代
Because we're iterating over and then
every iteration we have to iterate over
再一次重复我们迭代的每一次迭代
again, and then every one of those
iterations we iterate over again.
那么回去吧
So going back, Yeah,
我们在这里， n 的平方， n 到第三，就像你在 10 年一样，
we're out here, n squared, n to the third,
as you get n to the 10 whatever,
你会来这里但你永远也不会到达这条线的
you kind of get here but
you'll never get to this line really.
这就是诀窍这是一个简单的诡计
And that's the trick, it's a simple trick.
因此，将其应用于那些不需要外观的循环。
So apply that to things that are loops
that don't necessarily look like it.
这到底是什么东西
What's the big-O of this?
> n cubed?
&gt;&gt; n cubed?
> > 对， n 再到第三，是循环计数，
&gt;&gt; Yes, n to the third again,
it's count the loops,
每次你迭代的循环你都在迭代
every loop you're iterating over,
you're iterating over.
没有特别的，事实上，那是我的 Jem 提示，计算循环。
There's no special, well actually,
that's my Jem tip, count the loops.
有时候有点棘手我让它看起来是直的
It's a little tricky sometimes and
I make it seem straight forward in these
示例，但通常对 Big-O 时间有一些概念。
examples, but generally have
some idea of the Big-O time.